Guide to the Time Inc. The March of Time Audiovisual Collection 1979-1995 MS 3009-RG 15
New-York Historical Society
Time Inc. The March of Time Audiovisual Collection
1979-1995
New-York Historical Society
Time, inc.
MS 3009-RG 15
12.5 Linear feet in 13 record cartons.
The Time Inc. The March of Time Audiovisual Collection contains internal and commercially distributed audiovisual materials that were produced by The March of Time, a division of Time Inc. The materials were created between 1979 and 1995. The majority of records from The March of Time are in the Time Inc. Subject Files (MS 3009-RG 1) and Time Inc. Annex Files (MS 3009-RG 39).
Historical Note
The March of Time originally debuted on March 6, 1931 as radio newsreel on CBS Radio. The show was developed by Fred Smith, a radio executive, and Roy Larsen while he was the circulation director of Time. The two envisioned the show as a way to dramatize the news and reenact events that could not be reported live. At first, the show focused on domestic stories, but changed its focus at the beginning of World War II and began reporting on international events as well. In 1942, the show switched to providing straightforward news reports which relied on Time correspondents around the world instead of dramatized reenactments. The radio news program continued until 1945.
During The March of Time radio broadcast, Louis De Rochemont, a director of short films for Fox Movietone News, heard the show and had the idea for something he termed "pictoral journalism" which would recreate The March of Time on film. De Rochemont brought his idea to Larsen, and they began work on the film version of The March of Time in June 1934. The first episode of the film version debuted at the Capitol Theatre in New York City on February 1, 1935. While there had been newsreels shown before and between films before this point, their popularity had declined after the advent sound films. The March of Time would update and modernize the newsreels that had previously been seen. Unlike older versions of newsreels that avoided reporting on current events or anything controversial, The March of Time aimed to report events as they happened and included stories found on the pages of Time and Life. The show also included archival footage from the federal governemt, reenactments, interviews, and dramatic voice-overs. As the show matured and expanded, there were fewer reenactments and more interviews. With the rise of television and the costs of production, Time Inc. attempted to reduce the number films of The March of Time in the hope to reduce the costs while allowing the show to still exist. While this strategy did reduce costs, it also reduced profits. Due to budgetery issues, The March of Time newsreels ended in August 1951.
An attempt to relaunch the show was started in 1964. This relaunch would broadcast the show on the television channel WNEW instead of in theaters and was created together with the Metropolitan Broadcasting Company. While the original series provided news about current events, the relaunch appeared to have been about historical events and reused ideas and storylines from the original series. This version of the show did not last long and seems to have ended in 1966.
While in theaters, The March of Time delivered new newsreels on a monthly basis to thousands of theaters across the United States and abroad. At its peak, newsreels provided by The March of Time were played in 13,000 theaters and received forty awards and prizes including two Oscars from the Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences. Despite the awards and accolades, The March of Time was only profitable during two years of production, 1938 and 1939. Nevertheless, Time Inc. viewed The March of Time as a worthwhile vehicle to solidify its reputation as a news provider.
Citations:
Doll, Susan. "Introduction to THE MARCH OF TIME." Turner Classic Movies. Accessed October 24, 2018. http://www.tcm.com/this-month/article/343404|0/75th-Anniversary-of-The-March-of-Time.html.
Elson, Robert T., and Duncan Norton-Taylor. 1973. The World of Time Inc.: The Intimate History of a Publishing Enterprise, 1941-1960. New York: Atheneum.
National Radio Hall of Fame. "The March of Time." National Radio Hall of Fame. Accessed October 24, 2018. http://nationalradiohalloffame.com/march_of_time.htm.
Prendergast, Curtis, and Geoffrey Colvin. 1986. The World of Time Inc.: The Intimate History of a Changing Enterprise, 1960-1980. New York: Atheneum.
Scope and Contents
The The March of Time Audiovisual Collection contains videocassettes of episodes and clips of The March of Time. The majority of tapes were created for use within Time Inc. or for preservation purposes. A small amount include examples of the videocassettes produced for public purchase.
Unreformatted audiovisual and digital material in the collection is not accessible.
The majority of records from The March of Time along with the material regarding its history can be found in the Time Inc. Subject Files (MS 3009-RG 1) and Time Inc. Annex Files (MS 3009-RG 39). The Annex Files include scripts from the radio program, newsreels, and movie specials.
Arrangement
The record group is arranged into two series:
Series I. Audiovisual Materials for Internal Use
Series II. Commercially Distributed Audiovisual Materials
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Time Inc. in 2015.
Conditions Governing Access
Unreformatted audiovisual and digital material in the collection are not accessible. As the entire collection is audiovisual, it is all restricted at this time. Materials are stored offsite.
Related Materials
This finding aid relates to just one record group of the Time Inc. Records. For information about the other record groups and for overall information about the archives, please see the Guide to the Time Inc. Records (MS 3009). The Henry Luce Papers (MS 3014) were acquired with the Time Inc. Records. The collection of books acquired with the records are cataloged as the Time Inc. Reference Library.
The majority of records from The March of Time along with the material regarding its history can be found in the Time Inc. Subject Files (MS 3009-RG 1) and Time Inc. Annex Files (MS 3009-RG 39). The Annex Files include scripts from the radio program, newsreels, and movie specials.
Motion picture journalism; Newsreels; Videocassettes.; March of time (Motion picture); Time, inc. -- Archives; Time, inc. -- History
- Series I. Audiovisual Materials for Internal Use [RESTRICTED], 1979-1995, undated; 11 Linear feet in 11 record cartons
  Scope and Contents
  The Internal Use series contains videocassettes that were created for use within Time Inc. or for preservation purposes. These tapes mainly contain episodes of The March of Time but Time Warner: The Changing Face of Media and Entertainment is assumed to contain only clips from The March of Time. While the majority of tapes contain episodes from one volume, some tapes include episodes from multiple volumes.
  Arrangement
  Arranged in their original order by volume number and with special releases at the end. If a tape includes episodes from multiple volumes then that tape is placed with the earliest volume on the tape.
  - Untitled, undated (Offsite-box 2799, Item 1)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in.
  - Untitled, undated (Offsite-box 2799, Item 2)
  - The March of Time: Vol. 1 Issues 1-2, undated (Offsite-box 2799, Item 3)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 1 #1 Vol 2 #2"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 1 Issues 1-2, undated (Offsite-box 2799, Item 4)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 1 #1 Vol 1 #2"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 1 Issues 5-6, undated (Offsite-box 2799, Item 5)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 1 Ep 5/6"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 1 Issues 7-8, undated (Offsite-box 2799, Item 6)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 1 #7 Vol 1 #8"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 1 Issues 7-8, undated (Offsite-box 2799, Item 7)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 1 #7 Vol 1 #8"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 2 Issues 4-5, undated (Offsite-box 2799, Item 8)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 2 #4 Vol 2 #5"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 2 Issues 4-5, undated (Offsite-box 2799, Item 9)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 2 #4/5"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 2 Issues 6-7, undated (Offsite-box 2799, Item 10)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #2 Episode #6 Volume #2 Episode #7"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 2 Issues 6-7, undated (Offsite-box 2799, Item 11)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 2 #6 Vol 2 #7"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 2 Issues 6-7, undated (Offsite-box 2799, Item 12)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 2 #6/7"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 2 Issue 8 and Vol. 3 Issues 1-2, undated (Offsite-box 2799, Item 13)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 2 # 8 Vol 3 #1 Vol 3 #2"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 2 Issue 8 and Vol. 3 Issues 1-2, undated (Offsite-box 2799, Item 14)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 2 # 8 Vol 3 # 1 Vol 3 #2"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 3 Issues 3-4, undated (Offsite-box 2799, Item 15)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 3 #3 Vol 3 #4"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 3 Issues 3-4, undated (Offsite-box 2799, Item 16)
    1 videocasette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 3 #3 Vol 3 #4"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 3 Issues 5-7, undated (Offsite-box 2799, Item 17)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol #3 Episode #5, 6, and 7". Includes a note: "Vol. III Issue #5 THE FAR EAST (CHINA'S DICTATOR KIDNAPPED) Dec. 1936"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 3 Issues 5-7, undated (Offsite-box 2800, Item 1)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. Label on case is ripped, label on the videocassette states: "March of Time Vol #3 Episode #5, 6, and 7"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 3 Issue 7, undated (Offsite-box 2800, Item 2)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 3 #7"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 3 Issue 7, undated (Offsite-box 2800, Item 3)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 3 #7"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 3 Issues 8-9, undated (Offsite-box 2800, Item 4)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 3 #8/9"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 3 Issues 8-9, undated (Offsite-box 2800, Item 5)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 3 #8 Vol 3 #9"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 3 Issues 12-13, undated (Offsite-box 2800, Item 6)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #3 Episode #12 and 13"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 4 Issues 2-3, undated (Offsite-box 2800, Item 7)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #4 Episode #2 and 3"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 4 Issues 2-3, undated (Offsite-box 2800, Item 8)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #4 Episode #2 and 3"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 4 Issues 4-6, undated (Offsite-box 2800, Item 9)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #4 Episode #4, 5, and 6"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 4 Issues 4-6, undated (Offsite-box 2800, Item 10)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #4 Episode #4, 5, and 6"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 4 Issues 7-8, undated (Offsite-box 2800, Item 11)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: March of Time Vol 4 #7/8". Includes a note: "Vol. IV issue #8 ARMS AND THE LEAGUE March 1938"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 4 Issues 7-8, undated (Offsite-box 2800, Item 12)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 4 #7 Vol 4 #8". Includes a note: "TAPE BROKEN"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 4 Issue 9 and Vol. 8 Issue 13, undated (Offsite-box 2800, Item 13)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #4 Episode #9 Volume #8 Episode #13"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 4 Issue 9 and Vol. 8 Issue 13, undated (Offsite-box 2800, Item 14)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #4 Episode #9 Volume #8 Episode #13"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 4 Issues 10-11, undated (Offsite-box 2800, Item 15)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 4 #10/11"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 4 Issues 10-11, undated (Offsite-box 2800, Item 16)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 4 #10 Vol 4 #11"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 4 Issues 12-13, undated (Offsite-box 2801, Item 1)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #4 Episode #12 and 13"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 4 Issues 12-13, undated (Offsite-box 2801, Item 2)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 4 #12/13"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 4 Issues 12-13, undated (Offsite-box 2801, Item 3)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 4 #12 Vol 4 #13"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 5 Issues 1-2, undated (Offsite-box 2801, Item 4)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 5 #1/2"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 5 Issues 1-2, undated (Offsite-box 2801, Item 5)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 5 #1 Vol 5 #2".
  - The March of Time: Vol. 5 Issues 5-6, undated (Offsite-box 2801, Item 6)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #5 Episode #5 and 6"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 5 Issues 5-6, undated (Offsite-box 2801, Item 7)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #5 Episode #5 and 6"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 5 Issues 7-8, undated (Offsite-box 2801, Item 8)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #5 Episode #7 and 8"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 5 Issues 7-8, undated (Offsite-box 2801, Item 9)
    1 videocassette (U-Matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #5 Episode #7 and 8"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 5 Issues 9-10, undated (Offsite-box 2801, Item 10)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #5 Episode #9 and 10"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 5 Issues 9-10, undated (Offsite-box 2801, Item 11)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: " March of Time Volume #5 Episode #9 and 10"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 5 Issues 11-12, undated (Offsite-box 2801, Item 12)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 5 EP 11/12"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 5 Issues 12-13 and Vol. 6 Issue 1, undated (Offsite-box 2801, Item 13)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #5 Episode #12 and 13 Volume #6 Episode #1"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 5 Issues 12-13 and Vol. 6 Issue 1, undated (Offsite-box 2801, Item 14)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #5 Episode #12 and 13 Volume #6 Episode #1"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 6 Issues 2-3, undated (Offsite-box 2801, Item 15)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 6 #2 Vol 6 #3"
  - The March of Time: Vol 6 Issues 2-3, undated (Offsite-box 2801, Item 16)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 6 #2 Vol 6 #3"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 6 Issues 4-5, undated (Offsite-box 2802, Item 1)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #6 Episode #4 and 5"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 6 Issue 6, undated (Offsite-box 2802, Item 2)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 6 #6"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 6 Issue 6, undated (Offsite-box 2802, Item 3)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 6 #6"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 6 Issue 7, undated (Offsite-box 2802, Item 4)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 6 #7"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 6 Issue 7, undated (Offsite-box 2802, Item 5)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 6 #7"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 6 Issues 8-9, undated (Offsite-box 2802, Item 6)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #6 Episode #8 and 9"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 6 Issues 8-9, undated (Offsite-box 2802, Item 7)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #6 Episode #8 and 9"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 6 Issues 10-11, undated (Offsite-box 2802, Item 8)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #6 Episode #10 and 11"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 6 Issues 10-11, undated (Offsite-box 2802, Item 9)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #6 Episode #10 and 11"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 6 Issues 11-13, undated (Offsite-box 2802, Item 10)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #6 Episode #11, 12, and 13"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 6 Issues 11-13, undated (Offsite-box 2802, Item 11)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #6 Episode #11, 12, and 13"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 7 Issues 1-2, undated (Offsite-box 2802, Item 12)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #7 Episode #1 and 2"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 7 Issues 1-2, undated (Offsite-box 2802, Item 13)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #7 Episode #1 and 2"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 7 Issues 3-4, undated (Offsite-box 2802, Item 14)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #7 Episode #3 and 4"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 7 Issues 3-4, undated (Offsite-box 2802, Item 15)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #7 Episode #3 and 4"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 7 Issues 5-6, undated (Offsite-box 2803, Item 1)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #7 Episode #5 and 6"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 7 Issues 7-9, undated (Offsite-box 2803, Item 2)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #7 Episode #7, 8, and 9"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 7 Issues 7-9, undated (Offsite-box 2803, Item 3)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #7 Episode #7, 8, and 9"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 7 Issues 9-10, undated (Offsite-box 2803, Item 4)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Vol 7 EP 9/10"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 7 Issues 11-12, undated (Offsite-box 2803, Item 5)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume#7 Episode #11 and 12". Includes a note: "Vol. VII issue #11 CHINA FIGHTS BACK June 1941"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 7 Issues 11-12, undated (Offsite-box 2803, Item 6)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #7 Episode #11 and 12"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 7 Issue 13 and Vol. 8 Issues 1-2, undated (Offsite-box 2803, Item 7)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #7 Episode #13 Volume #8 Episode #1 annd 2"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 7 Issue 13 and Vol. 8 Issue 7, undated (Offsite-box 2803, Item 8)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #8 Episode #7 Volume #7 Episode #13"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 7 Issue 13 and Vol. 8 Issue 7, undated (Offsite-box 2803, Item 9)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #8 Episode #7 Volume #7 Episode 13"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 8 Issues 3-5, undated (Offsite-box 2803, Item 10)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #8 Episode #3, 4, and 5"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 8 Issues 6 and 8, undated (Offsite-box 2803, Item 11)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #8 Episode #6 Volume #8 Episode #8"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 8 Issues 6 and 8, undated (Offsite-box 2803, Item 12)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #8 Episode #6 Volume #8 Episode #8"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 8 Issues 9 and 11, undated (Offsite-box 2803, Item 13)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #8 Episode #9 and 11"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 8 Issues 12-13 and Vol. 9 Issue 1, undated (Offsite-box 2803, Item 14)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #8 Episode #12 and 13 Volume #9 Episode #1"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 8 Issues 12-13 and Vol. 9 Issue 1, undated (Offsite-box 2803, Item 15)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #8 Episode #12 and 13 Volume #9 Episode #1"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 9 Issue 2-4, undated (Offsite-box 2803, Item 16)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #9 Episode #2, 3, and 4"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 9 Issue 2-4, undated (Offsite-box 2804, Item 1)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #9 Episode #2, 3, and 4"
  - The March of Time: Vol 9 Issue 8 and Vol. 10 Issue 4, undated (Offsite-box 2804, Item 2)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #10 Episode #4 Volume #9 Episode #8"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 9 Issue 8 and Vol. 10 Issue 4, undated (Offsite-box 2804, Item 3)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #10 Episode #4 Volume #9 Episode #8"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 9 Issue 10-11, undated (Offsite-box 2804, Item 4)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On label on front of case and cassette: "March of Time Vol 9 EP 11/10". Label on side of case: "114. March of TIME 111/10/92 Vol 9 NOS?"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 10 Issue 1-2, undated (Offsite-box 2804, Item 5)
    1 videocassette (VHS): 1/2 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #10 Episode #1 and 2"
  - The March of Time: Vol. 10 Issue 1-2, undated (Offsite-box 2804, Item 6)
    1 videocassette (U-matic): 3/4 in. On case label and cassette label: "March of Time Volume #10 Episode #1 and 2"